<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-07-16T10:21:28-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Morrisa Neely</title><entry><title type="html">#100DaysOfCode, Day 6 and #30Days30Sites</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/16/100daysofcode-and-30days30sites" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="#100DaysOfCode, Day 6 and #30Days30Sites" /><published>2017-07-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-07-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/16/100daysofcode-and-30days30sites</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/16/100daysofcode-and-30days30sites">&lt;p&gt;So, I signed up for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.subscribepage.com/30days30sites&quot;&gt;#30Days30Sites&lt;/a&gt; challenge yesterday. First assignment? Build my portfolio. What had I just done on #100DaysOfCode Day 5? Built my &lt;a href=&quot;/portfolio&quot;&gt;portfolio&lt;/a&gt;. So I built a portfolio just for the challenge. &lt;a href=&quot;/portfolio/30Days30Sites&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is what I ended up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why circles? Because the rest of the world does rectangles in their galleries and portfolios and whatnot. I like being different. And circles are fun! Plus, thank goodness for stuff like Bootstrap, which makes the circles very easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping by the end of this, I’ll be better at HTML and CSS, a better designer, and maybe more able to slip Javascript into the stuff I’m building.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">So, I signed up for the #30Days30Sites challenge yesterday. First assignment? Build my portfolio. What had I just done on #100DaysOfCode Day 5? Built my portfolio. So I built a portfolio just for the challenge. This is what I ended up with.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">#100DaysOfCode, Day 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/15/100daysofcode-day-five" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="#100DaysOfCode, Day 5" /><published>2017-07-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-07-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/15/100daysofcode-day-five</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/15/100daysofcode-day-five">&lt;p&gt;Most of yesterday’s effort went into setting up a &lt;a href=&quot;/portfolio&quot;&gt;portfolio&lt;/a&gt;. I don’t really have much to put in a portfolio, but it was a good opportunity to do more experiments with HTML and CSS. I also used a dash of Bootstrap—with my own special touches, of course—which was interesting to play with. And sometimes frustrating, when I couldn’t get some layout-y things to do what I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end result, though? It was worth it. I don’t know about anyone else, but I think my blog &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; portfolio layouts are both pretty. They’re simple, but I like them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also managed to get a local copy of the blog running on my computer, which has made adjusting this thing a LOT more convenient.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Most of yesterday’s effort went into setting up a portfolio. I don’t really have much to put in a portfolio, but it was a good opportunity to do more experiments with HTML and CSS. I also used a dash of Bootstrap—with my own special touches, of course—which was interesting to play with. And sometimes frustrating, when I couldn’t get some layout-y things to do what I wanted.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">#100DaysOfCode, Day 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/14/100daysofcode-day-four" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="#100DaysOfCode, Day 4" /><published>2017-07-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-07-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/14/100daysofcode-day-four</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/14/100daysofcode-day-four">&lt;p&gt;Updating a day late, but better late than never, am I right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day Four of #100DaysOfCode mostly involved a battle between this blog’s footer and me. As you can see from the possibly-glaring absence of a footer, I was not successful. The footer will return once I figure out how to get it to stay down at the bottom, no matter what size the rest of the content is (not in a fixed position way, but in a way that doesn’t leave a gap between it and the bottom of the page).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t given up. I’m just taking a break to “lick my wounds” before taking another stab at the footer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also changed the colors and the background on here—I wanted something with more color. I love color. I’m the type of person who wears long, lemon-yellow coats with bright pink scarves. I love rainbows, sparkles, all of it. I used to paint, even, but that’s expensive, so I had to find other creative outlets. I felt my blog should reflect that part of me, which is what drew me to the rainbow cup photograph on Pixabay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(There may or may not be another reason why I love stuff with rainbows on it, but…well, I’m in a conservative part of the US and will likely be seeking a non-tech job soon, so. Plausable deniability. I hate that I have to be coy about that, because I’m not at all ashamed of it, but, you know—Bible Belt.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ANYWAY. I also did another essential bit of computer work yesterday: I cleaned my keyboard. And I started poking at a resume, which is pretty hard to make when you’ve never been employed anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Day Five, I’m either going to switch gears and find another HTML/CSS tutorial to work on, or try to figure out how to add tags to my blog posts. Haven’t decided yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for now, my lovelies. ♥&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Updating a day late, but better late than never, am I right?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">#100DaysOfCode Day 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/12/100daysofcode-day-three" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="#100DaysOfCode Day 3" /><published>2017-07-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/12/100daysofcode-day-three</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/12/100daysofcode-day-three">&lt;p&gt;Not as much done today as I would’ve liked. Had to go get my fake teeth adjusted a bit. As you can see, I tweaked the CSS on here a bit. I also did a little more tweaking of my YouTube video page clone for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theodinproject.com/courses/html5-and-css3/lessons/embedding-images-and-video?ref=lnav&quot;&gt;The Odin Project&lt;/a&gt; (code &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/morrisa-n/Odin-Project/tree/master/Projects/youtube&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;—I’m really not pleased with the code so far, and feel like it could be a &lt;em&gt;LOT&lt;/em&gt; better…but I’m not quite there in my skills yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I’ll do better. And it’s almost tomorrow already. ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Not as much done today as I would’ve liked. Had to go get my fake teeth adjusted a bit. As you can see, I tweaked the CSS on here a bit. I also did a little more tweaking of my YouTube video page clone for The Odin Project (code here—I’m really not pleased with the code so far, and feel like it could be a LOT better…but I’m not quite there in my skills yet).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/11/welcome-to-my-blog" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my blog" /><published>2017-07-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-07-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/11/welcome-to-my-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/11/welcome-to-my-blog">&lt;p&gt;Setting up a blog for my journey toward learning to program. Using Jekyll to set this thing up, along with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jmcglone.com/guides/github-pages/&quot;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt;. Hi!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Setting up a blog for my journey toward learning to program. Using Jekyll to set this thing up, along with this tutorial. Hi!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">#100DaysOfCode, Day Two</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/11/100daysofcode-day-two" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="#100DaysOfCode, Day Two" /><published>2017-07-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-07-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/11/100daysofcode-day-two</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/07/11/100daysofcode-day-two">&lt;p&gt;Day Two of my attempt at &lt;a href=&quot;http://100daysofcode.com/&quot;&gt;#100DaysofCode&lt;/a&gt;. This is my second time trying to do it. The first was toward the end of this June, but that ended up getting cut short by some major dental work—turns out getting nine teeth extracted and seven of those being replaced by a so-called “immediate denture” is very, very painful. Who knew?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…okay, I sort of had an idea it would be very painful, at least. It wasn’t my first tooth extraction rodeo. I’ve been dealing with bad teeth for years. I’m not even thirty yet, and I’ve got my first denture now. Genetic lottery winner right here, baby. *points at self*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway. Day Two. Today’s efforts have mostly been spent on this blog. I’m not happy with the layout, since it’s not much different from the tutorial I used to make the blog, but I am happy that I &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; got around to setting this thing up. Now I just need to make it more personal, add tags, and maybe add a few more custom touches and thingies.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Day Two of my attempt at #100DaysofCode. This is my second time trying to do it. The first was toward the end of this June, but that ended up getting cut short by some major dental work—turns out getting nine teeth extracted and seven of those being replaced by a so-called “immediate denture” is very, very painful. Who knew?</summary></entry></feed>